As I mentioned a little bit in the last lecture that projects are a temporary endeavor just because
they're temporary does not mean that it's a short term duration.
Often it projects.
We know that it's going to end at some point.
So that's the idea that it's temporary it's not ongoing.
And I said often a project is always and projects are temporary.
If there's no end in sight what a question am I doing operations projects have a definite beginning
and a definite ending.
Well we create the project charter.
What are the things that we put into the charter or what are the success criteria.
How do I know I'm done when these things are true.
So that's my goal that when I create these things I know the project is done.
So.
So that's the definite ending that projects are temporary projects are done or the projects end when
you meet those objectives.
No genitives doesn't have to be just the scope.
We could also have objectives like you have this much time there's a deadline and if you don't hit that
deadline there's no reason for the project to continue.
So for example we have a trade show you have to get this project done by this particular date in order
to be at the trade show.
Well if you missed the tradeshow day there's no reason for the project to go on and on projects might
also have an objective where there is a cost.
We have a limited amount of funds so we do the most important things first and then we do the least
important things that second so we're going to do as much as we can with the money that we have.
And when we run out of money and the projects done typically we think of scope driven but it could be
time or cost and we'll talk about an inverted triangle in an agile environment.
We'll talk about that coming up in just a little hint there keep you excited.
There might be a need no longer exists.
It could be that the project is no longer needed.
I'm rolling out version one that too of a piece of software in here comes version 2.0 right in the middle
of my project.
So my current project we know that needs to go away because we have a better technology now.
So it's no longer need it will go to project 2.0 or there's an opportunity in the marketplace and that
opportunity is gone.
So the projects are no longer needed would be a reason that projects could be canceled.
Resources may no longer be available.
So you might have a particular team member or skill set that you need.
And if that individual leave your organization then that puts your project in a real lurch could also
be that it's material that you're using a very specialized type of material.
And if you're having trouble getting that material then you know maybe your project is so dependent
on that it would no longer need to exist if you can't get that resource physical resource you might
have some legalities.
So there could be a new law or regulation that would cause your project to end because it would be out
of regulation or out of sync with the new law could also be just for convenience.
All right.
This project's gone on long enough.
We're done with that we're going to in the project.
So these are all characteristics of why a project is temporary really important to know because we want
to be able to recognize is this operations that it's ongoing or is it temporary.
We know it's going to end at some point and often we're thankful that it's going to end at some point.
All right good job.